# Yuanqing Ye

Software Engineer at Google

## Summary

I am a master's student in Electrical and Computer Engineering Department at Carnegie Mellon University. I am passionate in combining my knowledge with research work and applying my knowledge to real-life applications, especially in distributed system area and data analysis area. I have interned at Salesforce in the infrastructure team during Summer 2016 and I am going to work at Google from Spring 2017.

### Experience

#### **Software Engineer at Google**

February 2017 - Present

Currently I am in the F1 Database team.

#### Software Engineer Internship at Salesforce

May 2016 - August 2016 (4 months)

Reachability Scanner, as part of Software defined networking.

• Built the Reachability Scanner (RS): a network latency measurement, analysis and visualization system, which was

composed of the RS Controller, the RS Agent and the RS Collector

- Used pulling mode to make the RS Controller stateless & scalable and the RS Agent configurable & failclosed
- Pinpointed switch silent packet drops and end-to-end link failure by collecting and analyzing the ICMP echoes
- Visualized latency patterns and records of network SLAs by integrating WAVE analytics tool into the RS Collector

#### Graduate Teaching Assistant at Carnegie Mellon University

January 2016 - May 2016 (5 months)

Graduate Teaching Assistant for 15213 - Introduction to Computer Systems (SCS)

#### Education

#### **Carnegie Mellon University**

Master's Degree, Electrical and Computer Engineering, 2015 - 2016

#### **Huazhong University of Science and Technology**

Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng.), Electronics and Information Engineering, 2011 - 2015

# Yuanqing Ye

Software Engineer at Google



Contact Yuanqing on LinkedIn